{"data":[{"question":"I am going for a walk. _______you _______ (come) with me?","a":"Are\/coming","b":"Do\/come","c":"Does\/come","d":"Is\/coming","answer":"1","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking -> Present continuous.\n- Come -> coming.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"She usually _______ (play) cards or _______(watch) TV.","a":"plays\/watch","b":"is playing\/is watching","c":"play\/watches","d":"plays\/watches","answer":"4","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things (usually)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"Ann _______ (make) a dress for herself at the moment. She _______ (make) all her own clothes.","a":"is making\/is making","b":"makes\/is making","c":"is making\/makes","d":"makes\/makes","answer":"3","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking (at the moment) -> present continuous.\n- Talk about things are true in general -> present simple (makes all her own clothes).","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"I think it is a pity you don't take more exercise. You _______ (get) fat.","a":"get","b":"are getting","c":"gets","d":"is getting","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present continuous for things happening at the time of speaking","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"Look at that crowd. I _______ (wonder) what they _______ (wait) for.","a":"am wondering\/are waiting","b":"wonder\/are waiting","c":"am wondering\/wait","d":"wonder\/wait","answer":"2","explain":"- Talk about things in general -> present simple (wonder).\n- At or around the time of speaking -> present continuous (waiting).","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"_______you _______ (understand) what the lecturer is saying?\nNo, I _______ (not understand) him at all.","a":"Do you understand\/don't understand","b":"Are you understanding\/don't understand","c":"Do you understand\/am not understanding","d":"Are you understanding\/ am not understanding","answer":"1","explain":"- Understand is not normally used in the continuous.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"You can't see Tom now. He _______ (have) a bath.","a":"has","b":"are having","c":"have","d":"is having","answer":"4","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking (now) -> present continuous.\n- Have -> having.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"I'm busy at the moment. I _______ (redecorate) the sitting room.","a":"redecorate","b":"redecorating","c":"am redecorating","d":"are redecorating","answer":"3","explain":"- at or around the time of speaking (at the moment) -> present continuous.\n- redecorate -> redecorating.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"The kettle _______ (boil) now. Shall I make the tea?","a":"boils","b":"boil","c":"is boiling","d":"are boiling","answer":"3","explain":"- At or around the time of speaking (now) -> present continuous. \n- Boil -> boiling.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"},{"question":"Do you like this necklace?\nI _______(give) it to my daughter for her birthday tomorrow.","a":"give","b":"is giving","c":"am giving","d":"gives","answer":"3","explain":"- We use the present continuous when you have already decided and arranged to do something","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"5"}]}